The day I left home for the first time
يوم مغادرتي المنزل للمرة الاولى
to go to university was a bright day
لكي أذهب إلي الجامعه كان يوما مشرقاً
brimming with hope and optimism.
مفعماً بالأمل والتفاؤل
I'd done well at school. Expectations for me were high,
كنت جيدة في المدرسة . التوقعات لاجلي كانت عالية
and I gleefully entered the student life
و بابتهاج دخلت الحياة الطلابية من
of lectures, parties and traffic cone theft.
المحاضرات والاحتفلات و سرقة اللافتات الطرقية.
Now appearances, of course, can be deceptive,
إنّ المظاهر، بطبيعة الحال، يمكن أن تكون مخادعه,
and to an extent, this feisty, energetic persona
وإلى حد ما، هذه الشخصية المشاكسة، والنشطة
of lecture-going and traffic cone stealing was a veneer,
المواظبة على المحاضرات و سرقة اللافتات كانت فقط قشرة،
albeit a very well-crafted and convincing one.
ولو أنها وضعت بحرفية وبشكل مقنع.
Underneath, I was actually deeply unhappy, insecure
لكن من الداخل، كنت في الحقيقة تعيسهً جداً، وعديمة الثقة بنفسي
and fundamentally frightened --
وحقيقةً خائفة --
frightened of other people, of the future, of failure
خائفة من الآخرين، من المستقبل و من الفشل
and of the emptiness that I felt was within me.
ومن الفراغ الذي احسسته بداخلي.
But I was skilled at hiding it, and from the outside
لكنني كنت ماهرة في إخفائه، ومن الخارج
appeared to be someone with everything to hope for
بدَوت وكأني شخص لديه كل ما يتمناه
and aspire to.
ويطمح إليه.
This fantasy of invulnerability was so complete
هذه الصورة من الحصانة كانت مكتملة جداً
that I even deceived myself,
لدرجة أنني خدعت نفسي،
and as the first semester ended and the second began,
وكما انتهى الفصل الدراسي الأول بدأ الثاني,
there was no way that anyone could have predicted
وقد كان من المستحيل لأحد أن يتكهن
what was just about to happen.
مالذي كان على وشك الحدوث.
I was leaving a seminar when it started,
كنت مغادرة لندوة عندما بدأَ الأمر
humming to myself, fumbling with my bag
كنت أدندن لنفسي، أتحسس حقيبتي
just as I'd done a hundred times before,
تماما كما كنت أفعل مئات المرات من قبل،
when suddenly I heard a voice calmly observe,
عندها فجأة سمعت صوتاً هادءاً يقول:
"She is leaving the room."
"إنها تغادر الغرفة"
I looked around, and there was no one there,
نظرت حولي، ولم يكن هنالك أحد
but the clarity and decisiveness of the comment
ولكن وضوح وحسمية هذا التعليق
was unmistakable.
كان لا لبس فيها.
Shaken, I left my books on the stairs and hurried home,
مرتعشةً، تركت كتبي على السلالم وأسرعت إلى المنزل،
and there it was again.
وهناك تكرّر الأمر مجدّدا.
"She is opening the door."
"إنّها تفتح الباب."
This was the beginning. The voice had arrived.
تلك كانت البداية، لقد وصل الصوت.
And the voice persisted,
واستمر الصوت،
days and then weeks of it, on and on,
أياما ثم أسابيعا دون انقطاع
narrating everything I did in the third person.
سارداً كل ما فعلته بصيغة الغائب.
"She is going to the library."
" إنّها ذاهبة إلى المكتبة"
"She is going to a lecture."
" إنّها ذاهبة إلى محاضرة "
It was neutral, impassive and even, after a while,
لقد كان محايداً، خالياً من المشاعر، حتى أنه بعد فترة،
strangely companionate and reassuring,
أصبح مرافقاً ومطمئناً بشكل غريب
although I did notice that its calm exterior sometimes slipped
بالرغم من أنني لاحظت هدوءه الخارجي يتراجع أحياناً
and that it occasionally mirrored my own unexpressed emotion.
وأنّه يعكس في بعض الأحيان مشاعري المختبئة.
So, for example, if I was angry and had to hide it,
فمثلاً. إذا كنت غاضبة، وكان عليّ إخفائه،
which I often did, being very adept at concealing how I really felt,
و كثيراً ما كنت بارعة جداً في إخفاء ما أشعر به حقاً،
then the voice would sound frustrated.
عندها يبدو الصوت محبطاً.
Otherwise, it was neither sinister nor disturbing,
باستثناء ذلك، فلم يكن لا صوت شؤمٍ ولا مزعجاً،
although even at that point it was clear
بالرغم من أنه حتى في تلك المرحلة كان واضحاً
that it had something to communicate to me
أن لديه شيئا ليتواصل به معي
about my emotions, particularly emotions
عن مشاعري، تحديداً تلك المشاعر
which were remote and inaccessible.
التي كانت بعيدة ويصعب الوصول إليها.
Now it was then that I made a fatal mistake,
ولكن حينذاك قمت بخطأ فادح،
in that I told a friend about the voice, and she was horrified.
قمت بإخبار صديقة لي عن الصوت، فأصابها الهلع.
A subtle conditioning process had begun,
عملية تكييف دقيقة قد بدأت :
the implication that normal people don't hear voices
الإيحاء بأن الناس الطبيعيون لا يسمعون تلك أصوات
and the fact that I did meant that something was very seriously wrong.
وحقيقة أنني أسمعها فهذا يعني حقاً أن لديّ مشكلة جدّية .
Such fear and mistrust was infectious.
هذا الشعور بالخوف وعدم الثقة كان معدياً.
Suddenly the voice didn't seem quite so benign anymore,
فجأة لم يعد الصوت لطيفاً،
and when she insisted that I seek medical attention,
وعندما أصّرت عليّ لأذهب للرعاية الطبية،
I duly complied, and which proved to be
لبّيت طلبها، واللذي بدوره أثبت أنه
mistake number two.
الخطأ الثاني.
I spent some time telling the college G.P.
أمضيت بعض الوقت أحدّث الطبيب العام للكلية
about what I perceived to be the real problem:
عن ما اعتقدت أنها المشكلة الحقيقية:
anxiety, low self-worth, fears about the future,
القلق، عدم تقدير الذات، المخاوف بشأن المستقبل،
and was met with bored indifference
بالإضافة إلى اللامبالاة والملل
until I mentioned the voice,
حتى ذكرتُ الصوت.
upon which he dropped his pen, swung round
في تلك الحظة أوقع قلمه، عدّل جلسته
and began to question me with a show of real interest.
وبدأ يسألني باهتمام واضح.
And to be fair, I was desperate for interest and help,
ولكي نكون منصفين، كنت بحاجة ماسة للاهتمام والمساعدة،
and I began to tell him about my strange commentator.
وبدأت أخبره عن الصوت الغريب.
And I always wish, at this point, the voice had said,
وكنت أتمنى دائماً لو أنه في تلك اللحظة قال الصوت:
I was referred to a psychiatrist, who likewise
تمت إحالتي على طبيب نفسي، والذي بدوره
took a grim view of the voice's presence,
نظر بجدّية إلى مسألة وجود الصوت،
subsequently interpreting everything I said
مقاطعاً كلامي كلّما تكلّمت
through a lens of latent insanity.
ويظهر كدليل على حالة جنون كامنة.
For example, I was part of a student TV station
مثلا، كنت جزء من محطة تلفزيونية للطلاب
that broadcast news bulletins around the campus,
والتي كانت تبث الأخبار في جميع أنحاء الحرم الجامعي،
and during an appointment which was running very late,
وفي أثناء موعدٍ حدث في وقت متأخر جداً،
I said, "I'm sorry, doctor, I've got to go.
قلت له: "أنا آسفة دكتور، يجب أن أذهب.
I'm reading the news at six."
عليّ قراءة نشرة الأخبار في السادسة "
Now it's down on my medical records that Eleanor
و الآن يوجد في سجليّ الطبي أنّ إليانور
It was at this point that events began
وعند هذه النقطة كانت قد بدأت الأحداث
to rapidly overtake me.
تغمرني بسرعة.
A hospital admission followed, the first of many,
تبع ذلك دخول المستشفى، وهو الأمر الأول من العديد من الأشياء،
a diagnosis of schizophrenia came next,
التشخيص بانفصام في الشخصية جاء تالياً،
and then, worst of all, a toxic, tormenting sense
ومن ثم، الأسوأ من ذلك كله كان هناك شعور مسموم وقاتل
of hopelessness, humiliation and despair
باليأس، الذل و الخنوع
about myself and my prospects.
تجاه نفسي و آمالي.
But having been encouraged to see the voice
ولكن بعد تشجيعي على التّعرف على صوت
not as an experience but as a symptom,
ليس كتجربة ولكن كمرض,
my fear and resistance towards it intensified.
ازداد خوفي ومقاومتي له.
Now essentially, this represented taking
بشكل أساسي، كان هذا بمثابة أخذ
an aggressive stance towards my own mind,
موقف عدائي تجاه عقلي
a kind of psychic civil war,
نوع من الحرب الأهلية النفسية،
and in turn this caused the number of voices to increase
وهذا بدوره تسبب في زيادة عدد الأصوات
and grow progressively hostile and menacing.
ونموّها تدريجياً بشكل عدائي وكتهديد.
Helplessly and hopelessly, I began to retreat
بلا حول ولا قوة، بدأت أتراجع
into this nightmarish inner world
إلى هذا العالم الداخلي الكابوسي
in which the voices were destined to become
اللذي فيه كان مقدّر للأصوات أن تصبح
both my persecutors and my only perceived companions.
مدتهضتي، و رفيقتي الوحيدة في آن معاً.
They told me, for example, that if I proved myself worthy
قالوا لي، على سبيل المثال، أنه إذا أثبت أنني جديرة
of their help, then they could change my life
بمساعادتهم، عندها يمكنهم إرجاع حياتي
back to how it had been,
إلى ما كانت عليه.
and a series of increasingly bizarre tasks was set,
و بدأت سلسلة من المهمات الغريبة
a kind of labor of Hercules.
أشبه بأعمال (هرقل).
It started off quite small, for example,
بدأت بداية صغيرة جداً، على سبيل المثال،
pull out three strands of hair,
اسحبي ثلاثة جدائل من الشعر،
but gradually it grew more extreme,
ولكنها تدريجياً نمت أكثر تطرفاً،
culminating in commands to harm myself,
وبلغت ذروتها في أوامر لإيذاء نفسي،
and a particularly dramatic instruction:
و بشكل خاص أحد الأوامر الدرامية:
"You see that tutor over there?
"أترين ذلك الأستاذ هناك؟
You see that glass of water?
أترين كوب الماء ذلك؟
Well, you have to go over and pour it over him in front of the other students."
حسنا، يجب عليك الذهاب وسكبه فوق رأسه أمام الطلاب الآخرين."
Which I actually did, and which needless to say
وهو في الحقيقة ما فعلته، ولا حاجة للقول
did not endear me to the faculty.
أنه لم يلق إعجاب الجامعة.
In effect, a vicious cycle of fear, avoidance,
في الواقع، حلقة مفرغة من الخوف، والهروب،
mistrust and misunderstanding had been established,
عدم الثقة وسوء الفهم كانت قد تشكّلت
and this was a battle in which I felt powerless
وقد كانت معركة شعرت فيها بالعجز
and incapable of establishing any kind of peace or reconciliation.
وغير قادرة على تكوين أي نوع من السلام أو المصالحة.
Two years later, and the deterioration was dramatic.
بعد ذلك بعامين، كان تدهوري دراماتيكياً
By now, I had the whole frenzied repertoire:
حتى الآن، كت أعاني من جميع أعراض الحمّى :
terrifying voices, grotesque visions,
الاصوات المرعبة، والرؤى البشعة،
bizarre, intractable delusions.
الأوهام الغريبة و الصعبة.
My mental health status had been a catalyst
كانت حالتي الصحية النفسية محفّزاً
for discrimination, verbal abuse,
للتمييز والإساءة اللفظية،
and physical and sexual assault,
والاعتداء الجسدي والجنسي,
and I'd been told by my psychiatrist,
وقد قال لي طبيبي النفسي :
"Eleanor, you'd be better off with cancer,
"إليانور، كنتي لتكوني أفضل حالاً مع مرض السرطان،
because cancer is easier to cure than schizophrenia."
لأنّ السرطان أسهل علاجاً من مرض انفصام الشخصية."
I'd been diagnosed, drugged and discarded,
تم تشخيصي، تخديري و إهمالي،
and was by now so tormented by the voices
وكنت الآن معذبة بشدة من قبل الأصوات
that I attempted to drill a hole in my head
لدرجة أني حاولت أن حفر حفرة في رأسي
in order to get them out.
لإخراجها.
Now looking back on the wreckage and despair of those years,
بالنظر الآن مرة أخرى إلى الحطام واليأس في تلك السنوات،
it seems to me now as if someone died in that place,
يبدو لي الآن وكأن شخصاً ما قد مات في ذلك المكان،
and yet, someone else was saved.
ولكن شخصا أخر قد تم إنقاذه.
A broken and haunted person began that journey,
شخص مكسور ومجروح قد بدأ تلك الرحلة،
but the person who emerged was a survivor
ولكن الشخص الذي خرج كان ناجياً
and would ultimately grow into the person
و سوف ينمو في النهاية ليصبح الشخص
I was destined to be.
اللذي أمثّله انا الآن.
Many people have harmed me in my life,
كثير من الناس آذوني في حياتي،
and I remember them all,
وأنا أتذكرهم جميعا ً
but the memories grow pale and faint
لكن الذكريات تنمو شاحبة وباهتة
in comparison with the people who've helped me.
بالمقارنة مع الناس الذين ساعدوني.
The fellow survivors, the fellow voice-hearers,
رفاقي الناجين، رفاقي سامعي الأصوات،
the comrades and collaborators;
الأصدقاء والمتعاونين،
the mother who never gave up on me,
الأم التي لم تتخلى عني بتاتاً،
who knew that one day I would come back to her
التي كانت على علم أنني سأعود إليها
and was willing to wait for me for as long as it took;
والتي كانت على استعداد لانتظاري مهما استغرقت من الوقت.
the doctor who only worked with me for a brief time
الطبيب الذي عمل معي لفترة وجيزة فقط
but who reinforced his belief that recovery
لكنه عزز من اعتقاده بأن الشفاء
was not only possible but inevitable,
ليس ممكناً فحسب، بل حتمياً،
and during a devastating period of relapse
وخلال فترة مدمرة من الانتكاس
told my terrified family, "Don't give up hope.
أخبر أسرتي المرعوبة "لا تفقدوا الأمل.
I believe that Eleanor can get through this.
وأعتقد بأن (إلينور) بإمكانها تخطي ذلك.
Sometimes, you know, it snows as late as May,
أحياناً، كما تعلمون، إن الثلوج تتساقط في وقت متأخر من شهر حزيران،
but summer always comes eventually."
ولكن الصيف يأتي دائما في نهاية المطاف."
Fourteen minutes is not enough time
أربعة عشر دقيقة ليست وقتا كافياً
to fully credit those good and generous people
لكي أشكر أولئك الذين كانوا كريمين وطيبين
who fought with me and for me
الذين حاربوا معي ولأجلي
and who waited to welcome me back
والذين انتظروا ليرحبوا بعودتي
from that agonized, lonely place.
من ذلك المكان المعذِب و المعزول.
But together, they forged a blend of courage,
لكنهم معاً شكّلوا مزيجاً من الشجاعة
creativity, integrity, and an unshakeable belief
و الإبداع والنزاهة والإيمان الذي لا يتزعزع
that my shattered self could become healed and whole.
بأنّ نفسي المحطمة يمكن أن تصبح ملتئمة ومكتملة.
I used to say that these people saved me,
كنت أقول أن هؤلاء الناس أنقذوا حياتي،
but what I now know is they did something
ولكن ما أعرفه الآن هو أنّهم فعلوا شيئاً
even more important in that they empowered me
أكثر أهمية حيث أنهم جعلوني أقوى
to save myself,
لكي أنقذ نفسي،
and crucially, they helped me to understand something
والأهم، أنهم ساعدوني على فهم شيء
which I'd always suspected:
واللذي لم أكن أبداً متأكدة منه:
that my voices were a meaningful response
أن تلك الأصوات كانت استجابة ذات مغزى
to traumatic life events, particularly childhood events,
لأحداث الحياة المؤلمة، وخاصة أحداث في مرحلة الطفولة،
and as such were not my enemies
وعلى هذا النحو لم تكن عدوّتي
but a source of insight into solvable emotional problems.
لكن مصدراً من البصيرة داخل المشاكل العاطفية القابلة للحل.
Now, at first, this was very difficult to believe,
في البداية، كان من الصعب تصديق هذا
not least because the voices appeared so hostile
على الأقل لأن الأصوات كانت عدائية جداً
and menacing, so in this respect, a vital first step
ومهددة لذا في هذا الشأن، ظهرت خطوة أولى
was learning to separate out a metaphorical meaning
وهي أن أتعلم فصل المعاني المجازية
from what I'd previously interpreted to be a literal truth.
عن ما فسرته سابقاً على أنه الحقيقة الواقعية.
So for example, voices which threatened to attack my home
فعلى سبيل المثال، الأصوات التي هددت بمهاجمة بيتي
I learned to interpret as my own sense of fear
تعلمت أن أفسّرها على انها أحاسيسي الخاصة بالخوف
and insecurity in the world, rather than an actual, objective danger.
وانعدام الأمان في العالم، بدلا من أن تكون خطراً حقيقياً.
Now at first, I would have believed them.
الآن في البداية، كنت أصدقهم
I remember, for example, sitting up one night
أتذكر، على سبيل المثال، بقائي في ليلة من الليالي
on guard outside my parents' room to protect them
أحرس باب غرفة والدي لحمايتهم
from what I thought was a genuine threat from the voices.
عن ما اعتقدت بأنّه تهديد حقيقي من الأصوات.
Because I'd had such a bad problem with self-injury
ولأنه كانت لدي تلك المشكلة الكبيرة بإيذاء النفس
that most of the cutlery in the house had been hidden,
لدرجة أن معظم أدوات المائدة في المنزل كانت مخبأة.
so I ended up arming myself with a plastic fork,
حتى انتهى بي الأمر بحماية نفسي بشوكة بلاستيكية
kind of like picnic ware, and sort of sat outside the room
نوع من نزهة ما، جلست خارج الغرفة
clutching it and waiting to spring into action should anything happen.
ممسكة بها و منتظرة الإندفاع في حال حدوث أي شيء.
It was like, "Don't mess with me.
كأني أقول "لا تعبث معي.
I've got a plastic fork, don't you know?"
لدي شوكة بلاستيكية، ألا تعلم ذلك ؟"
Strategic.
خطة استراتيجية.
But a later response, and much more useful,
ولكن إستجابة متأخرة، وبفائدة أكبر
would be to try and deconstruct the message behind the words,
ستكون بمحاولة قراءة الرسالة مابين السطور،
so when the voices warned me not to leave the house,
لذا عندما حذرتني الأصوات من عدم مغادرة المنزل،
then I would thank them for drawing my attention
حينذاك وددت أن أشكرهم على لفت انتباهي
to how unsafe I felt --
لفكرة عدم شعوري بالأمان --
because if I was aware of it, then I could do something positive about it --
لأنه لو كنت على علم بها، لفعلت شيئاً إيجابياً حيال ذلك --
but go on to reassure both them and myself
ولكن عليّ أن أطمئنهم وأطمئن نفسي
that we were safe and didn't need to feel frightened anymore.
بأننا كنا آمنين ولا نحتاج لأن نشعر بالخوف بعد الآن.
I would set boundaries for the voices,
أريد أن أضع حدودا للأصوات،
and try to interact with them in a way that was assertive
وأن أحاول التعامل معها بطريقة حازمة
yet respectful, establishing a slow process
ولكن باحترام، تكوين عملية بطيئة
of communication and collaboration
من التواصل والتعاون
in which we could learn to work together and support one another.
نستطيع من خلالها تعلم كيفية العمل معاً ودعم بعضنا البعض.
Throughout all of this, what I would ultimately realize
عبر كل ذلك، ما يمكن أن ندركه في نهاية المطاف
was that each voice was closely related
هو أنّ كل صوت كان وثيق الصلة
to aspects of myself, and that each of them
بجوانبي النفسية، وأنّ كل واحد منها
carried overwhelming emotions that I'd never had
يحمل مشاعر عارمة، تلك التي لم أمتلكها يوماً
an opportunity to process or resolve,
الفرصة لمعالجتها أو تسويتها،
memories of sexual trauma and abuse,
ذكريات الصدمة والاعتداء الجنسي،
of anger, shame, guilt, low self-worth.
الغضب والخجل، والشعور بالذنب، وانخفاض تقدير الذات.
The voices took the place of this pain
أخذت الأصوات مكان هذا الألم
and gave words to it,
و غلّفته بكلمات.
and possibly one of the greatest revelations
وربما واحدة من أعظم الاكتشافات
was when I realized that the most hostile and aggressive voices
كان عندما أدركت أن أكثر الأصوات المعادية والعدائية
actually represented the parts of me
كان يمثّل في الواقع أجزاء منّي
that had been hurt most profoundly,
والتي كانت قد تأذت بعمق،
and as such, it was these voices
وبالتالي، كانت الأصوات هي
that needed to be shown the greatest compassion and care.
التي تحتاج إلى عطف ورعاية كبيران.
It was armed with this knowledge that ultimately
كانت مسلّحة بهذه المعرفة، وفي نهاية المطاف
I would gather together my shattered self,
كنت سأجمع شتات نفسي،
each fragment represented by a different voice,
كل جزء مني يمثله صوت مختلف،
gradually withdraw from all my medication,
أنسحب تدريجياً من كل علاجاتي،
and return to psychiatry, only this time from the other side.
وأعود إلى الطبيب النفسي، لكن هذه المرة من الجانب الآخر.
Ten years after the voice first came, I finally graduated,
بعد 10 سنوات من ظهور أول صوت، أخيراً تخرّجت
this time with the highest degree in psychology
هذه المرة مع أعلى درجة في علم النفس
the university had ever given, and one year later,
كانت قد منحتها أيّ جامعة في أي وقت مضى، وبعد عام واحد
the highest masters, which shall we say
أعلى درجات الماجستير، ولنقل
isn't bad for a madwoman.
أن ليس أمراً سيئاً بالنسبة لإمرأة مجنونة.
In fact, one of the voices actually dictated the answers
حقيقة، واحدة من الأصوات في الواقع أملى عليّ الإجابات
during the exam, which technically possibly counts as cheating.
أثناء الامتحان، وذلك يعتبر ربما تقنيا غشّا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And to be honest, sometimes I quite enjoyed their attention as well.
ولنكون صادقين، أحيانا لقد استمتعت تماما بانتباههم وكذلك
As Oscar Wilde has said, the only thing worse
كما قال أوسكار وايلد، الشيء الوحيد السيئ
It also makes you very good at eavesdropping,
كما أنه يجعلك جيدة جدا في التنصت
because you can listen to two conversations simultaneously.
لأنه يمكنك الاستماع إلى محادثتين في نفس الوقت
I worked in mental health services,
عملت في خدمات الصحة النفسية
I spoke at conferences,
تكلمت في مؤتمرات
I published book chapters and academic articles,
نشرت فصول من كتاب و مقالات أكديمية
and I argued, and continue to do so,
تجادلت وسأواصل افعل ذلك
the relevance of the following concept:
أهمية المفهوم التالي
that an important question in psychiatry
إنّ السؤال المهم في الطب النفسي
shouldn't be what's wrong with you
لا ينبغي أن يكون ما هو الخطب فيك
but rather what's happened to you.
بل ما الذي حدث لك.
And all the while, I listened to my voices,
وكل حين، كنت استمع إلى أصواتي
with whom I'd finally learned to live with peace and respect
مع الذين كنت تعلمت أخيرا العيش في سلام واحترام
and which in turn reflected a growing sense
والذي ينعكس بدوره شعور متزايد
of compassion, acceptance and respect towards myself.
من التعاطف والقبول والاحترام تجاه نفسي
And I remember the most moving and extraordinary moment
وأتذكر اللحظات الأكثر إثارة للمشاعر وغير اعتيادية
when supporting another young woman who was terrorized by her voices,
عند دعم شابة أخري تعاني من ترهيب من قبل أصواتها
and becoming fully aware, for the very first time,
وأصبحت على وعي تام، للمرة الأولى
that I no longer felt that way myself
أنني لم اعد اشعر بهذه الطريقة بنفسي
but was finally able to help someone else who was.
وبكوني في آخر قادرة على مساعدة شخص آخر.
I'm now very proud to be a part of Intervoice,
أنا الآن فخورة جدا أن أكون جزءا من أنترفويز
the organizational body of the International Hearing Voices Movement,
المنظّمة الخاصة بسماعي الأصوات الدولية،
an initiative inspired by the work of Professor Marius Romme
مبادرة مستوحاة من أعمال البروفسير ماريوس رومي
and Dr. Sandra Escher,
والدكتورة ساندرا ايشر
which locates voice hearing as a survival strategy,
والذي يحدد سماعي الاصوات كاستراتيجية بقاء
a sane reaction to insane circumstances,
كرد فعل عاقل لظروف مجنونة
not as an aberrant symptom of schizophrenia to be endured,
وليس بوصفه من الأعراض الشاذة من مرض انفصام الشخصية يجب تحملها،
but a complex, significant and meaningful experience
ولكن لجمع، خبرة كبيرة وذات مغزى
to be explored.
يتعين استكشافها
Together, we envisage and enact a society
معا فإننا نتصور و نشكّل مجتمعا
that understands and respects voice hearing,
أن يفهم ويحترم سامعي الاصوات
supports the needs of individuals who hear voices,
ويدعم احتياجات الافراد من سامعي الاصوات
and which values them as full citizens.
و تقديرهم كمواطنين كاملي الحقوق.
This type of society is not only possible,
هذا النوع من المجتمع ليس ممكنا فحسب
it's already on its way.
انه بالفعل في الطريق.
To paraphrase Chavez, once social change begins,
بتعبير شافيز " بمجرد أن يبدأ التغيير الاجتماعي،
it cannot be reversed.
فإنه لا يمكن عكسه."
You cannot humiliate the person who feels pride.
لا يمكنك إذلال الشخص الذي يشعر بالفخر
You cannot oppress the people
لا يمكنك قمع الشعب
who are not afraid anymore.
الذين لا يخافون بعد الآن.
For me, the achievements of the Hearing Voices Movement
بالنسبة لي، فإن إنجازات حركة سماعي الأصوات
are a reminder that empathy, fellowship,
هي تذكير بأن التعاطف، الزمالة
justice and respect are more than words;
العدالة والاحترام هي أكثر من مجرد كلمات؛
they are convictions and beliefs,
فهي قناعات ومعتقدات
and that beliefs can change the world.
وتلك المعتقدات يمكن أن تغيّر العالم.
In the last 20 years, the Hearing Voices Movement
في السنوات ال20 الماضية، حركة سماعي الأصوات
has established hearing voices networks
قد أنشأت شبكات سماعي أصوات
in 26 countries across five continents,
في 26 بلدا عبر القارات الخمس،
working together to promote dignity, solidarity
تعمل معا لتعزيز الكرامة والتضامن
and empowerment for individuals in mental distress,
و لتمكين الأفراد من الاضطرابات النفسية
to create a new language and practice of hope,
من لخلق لغة جديدة وممارسات من الأمل
which, at its very center, lies an unshakable belief
والتي تتمركز في ارساء إيمان لا يتزعزع
in the power of the individual.
في قوة الفرد.
As Peter Levine has said, the human animal
كما قال بيتر ليفين، حيوان الإنسان
is a unique being
هو كائن فريد من نوعه
endowed with an instinctual capacity to heal
له مع القدرة الغريزية للشفاء
and the intellectual spirit to harness this innate capacity.
وروح الفكرية لتسخير هذه القدرات الفطرية.
In this respect, for members of society,
في هذا الصدد، لأفراد المجتمع
there is no greater honor or privilege
ليس هناك شرف أعظم أو امتياز
than facilitating that process of healing for someone,
من تسهيل تلك العملية من الشفاء لشخص،
to bear witness, to reach out a hand,
ليشهد و ليصل
to share the burden of someone's suffering,
إلى تقاسم عبء معاناة شخص ما،
and to hold the hope for their recovery.
وعقد الأمل في شفائهم.
And likewise, for survivors of distress and adversity,
وبالمثل، للناجين من الشدة والمحن
that we remember we don't have to live our lives
أنّ علينا أن نتذكر أننا لا نملك أن نعيش حياتنا
forever defined by the damaging things that have happened to us.
عن طريق التعريف بالاضرار التي حدثت لنا.
We are unique. We are irreplaceable.
نحن فريدون. و لا يمكن الاستغناء عنا.
What lies within us can never be truly colonized,
ما يكمن في داخلنا لا يمكن أبدا أن تكون مستعمرة حقا،
contorted, or taken away.
ملتوية، أو اتخذت بعيدا.
The light never goes out.
ضوء لا ينطفئ أبدا.
As a very wonderful doctor once said to me,
كما قال لي طبيب رائع جدا يوما
"Don't tell me what other people have told you about yourself.
"لا تخبرني عن ما يجب الآخرون قوله عن نفسك،
Tell me about you."
أخبرني عنك."
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
تصفيق